Christopher Blow France

Design director, programmer, strategist

Hello, I'm Christopher. I am a designer, programmer and usability researcher. I am passionate about strategies for the improvement of civil society and environmental resilience. I've helped implement large digital products with organizations such as Sony, Facebook, Cambridge University and The Data Guild.

Work experience

LightField

CO-FOUNDER AND PARTNER: MARCH 2019 - CURRENT

LightField is using design and data strategy for regenerative agriculture, with a focus on innovation in financial products serving this sector. We are developing business partnerships around our data products with a goal of increasing the rate of regenerative transition through increased investment opportunities based on improved soil health.

Healthmade

CREATIVE DATA TECHNOLOGIST: SEPTEMBER 2019 - CURRENT

At Healthmade I work to invent creative solutions to healthcare issues using web and mobile prototyping, UI design and data visualization. My focus is building tools to serve people living with chronic illness.

Contain

LEAD TECHNOLOGIST: JULY 2019 - CURRENT

At Contain I designed and built a fintech platform which algorithmically matches lenders and borrowers in contained agriculture, an emergent technique which uses approximately 10x less resources than conventional agriculture.

Litterati

DATA PRODUCT STRATEGIST: MAY 2019 - CURRENT

Litterati is an environmental startup that uses crowdsourced data derived from local litter cleanup activity to create a large commercial dataset of consumer packaging data. I help with partnership and commercial strategy by designing and prototyping data refinement tools used by the team.

The Data Guild

LEAD MEMBER: JULY 2018 - CURRENT

As a lead member of our venture studio, I am responsible for a wide range activity in a data-intensive environment. I do partnerships, business process design, business development, hiring and client services. My focus is prototyping new technical capacity and creating production designs — from sketching and wireframing to JavaScript, pitch decks and business plans.

Meedan

DESIGN DIRECTOR: MARCH 2008 - JULY 2018

Meedan is a technology services company focused on translation and communication technology. Meedan has a goal to create more meaning in the world. Meedan works as a technology consultancy with large social networks such as Facebook. I operated the design process and all aspects of our user research strategy. I led the team responsible for graphic design, front-end code, design systems and strategies to support a product team creating new media projects.

Bolt | Peters User Experience

RESEARCHER, DEVELOPER & DESIGNER: JULY 2007 - SEPTEMBER 2008

I was responsible for designing studies, analyzing results, collaborating with clients. I created videos, wireframes and sketches. I helped design and build Ethnio, a digital product for the user experience industry.

Blast Internet Services

DIRECTOR OF OPERATIONS: MARCH 2006 - JULY 2007

I revitalized a web consulting business with a user-centric voice. I implemented an Agile development methodology and the Rails stack.

Evaluation, Assessment and Policy Connections

WEB DEVELOPER, PROGRAM ASSISTANT: MAY 2004 - MARCH 2006

I developed applications for managing stakeholder data, creating educational surveys and gathering real-time feedback.

Nonprofit Design

WEB DEVELOPER, FOUNDER: MAY 2003 - MARCH 2006

I operated a consultancy with clients such as Duke University and the University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill.

The North Carolina Law Review

WEB DEVELOPER: AUGUST 2001 - DECEMBER 2003

I helped create a custom database for the Law Review, and I managed their website.

Speaking

In the last few years I've given a variety of presentations at events like RightsCon, Global Fact, the Online News Association, DrupalCon, the International CrisisMappers Conference, SXSW, the African News Innovation Challenge, the Nonprofit Technology Conference, the NYU Interactive Telecommunications Program and Stanford.

Awards

A number of projects that I worked on have won awards recently, an Online Journalism Award (for Electionland, one of the largest journalistic collaborations in the U.S.), the International Press Institute News Innovation Contest, the Innovate Africa Innovation Challenge and the Knight News Challenge for Prototypes.

Education

University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill Mass Communications JUNE 2001 - JANUARY 2004

Bachelor of Arts

University of North Carolina at Asheville Humanities, music, literature

AUGUST 1998 - DECEMBER 2001

Bachelor of Arts

(415) 309-7900 • christopher@lightfield.ag • 94611 • Oakland • California, USA